你豈不曾聽見
Have you not heard?
永在的神耶和華
The Lord is the everlasting God.
創造地極的主
Creator of the ends of the earth.
並不疲乏 也不睏倦
He will not grow tired or weary.
他的智慧無法測度
And his understanding no one can fathom.
疲乏的 他賜能力
He gives strength to the weary,
軟弱的 他加力量
and increases the power to the weak.
就是少年人也要疲乏睏倦
Even youth grow tired and weary,
強壯的也必全然跌倒
and young man stumble and fall,
但那等候耶和華的
but those who hope in the Lord
必重新得力
will renew their strength.
他們必如鷹展翅上騰
They will soar on wings like eagles.
他們奔跑
They will run
卻不睏倦
and not be weary.
他們行走
They will walk
卻不疲乏
and not be faint.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
撐住
Hang on.
撐住 戴斯蒙德
Hang on, Desmond.
我們會帶你離開這裏
We're gonna get you outta here.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
怎麼了
What?
等等
Wait up.
跟上
Catch up.
等等 我有事要和你說
Wait up. I got something to tell you.
哈爾 怎麼了
What, Hal?
看誰先跑到山頂
Race you to the top.
嘿 騙子
Hey, cheater!
再見 小短腿
See you later, slowpoke.
嘿
Hey.
要拉你一把嗎
You wanna hand?
我能行
I got it.
下去吧
Saved you.
別亂動 別鬧
Ah, you don't. Quit it.
你別鬧
You quit it.
天哪
For Pete's sake.
別站在懸崖邊上
Hey, get away from that ledge.
你們這兩個愚蠢的小鬼
You damn fool kids.
你們會摔斷脖子的
You gonna break your neck.
是道斯家的孩子
It's them. Doss kids.
和他們爸爸一樣瘋
Crazy as their old man.
他們新開了塊地 就在傑克遜大街拐角...
They dug up the corner of Jackson and Main...
鋪上了人行道...
Putting in the sidewalk...
你們現在肯定都認不出了
You boys wouldn't recognize it now.
他們可能連你們也認不出了吧
Mind you, I doubt they'll recognize you.
我路過的時候 他們都不認識我了
They hardly know me when I walk by 'em.
就好像我和你們一起死了
It's like I died with you.
就好像我們從來就不曾存在過
It's like we boys never existed.
我今天就想說這麼多
Well, that's all I got for you today.
戴斯蒙德 用你的右手擋住他
Block him with your right, Desmond.
住手
Stop it.
你們聽到了嗎
Do you hear me?
他們為什麼要打架
What are they fighting about?
他們打架還需要理由嗎
When did they ever need a reason?
湯姆 你就...
Hey, Tom, do you...
為什麼要管 省得我還得揍他們兩個
Why stop 'em? Saves me whipping them both.
這樣我只需要揍贏的那個
This way, I'd whip the one that wins.
湯姆
Tom.
不
No!
天哪
Oh God.
湯姆
Tom!
醒醒 能聽到我說話嗎
Wake up. Can you hear me?
你他媽的做了什麼
What the hell have you done?
他沒有意識了
He can't hear me.
讓我來
I got it.
我去找些冰塊
I'll get some ice.
把籃子拿開
You shift that basket.
我來
I got it.
他還有呼吸嗎
Is he breathing?
哈爾
Hal?
哈爾 能聽見我說話嗎
Hal, can you hear me?
哈爾
Hal?
醒醒
Come on.
上帝啊 救救他吧
Dear God help him.
哈爾
Hal...
你知道自己在幹什麼嗎
What do you think you doing?
我現在要揍你了
I'm going to have to beat you now.
你知道規矩
You know the rules.
你聽到了嗎 戴斯蒙德
You hear me, Desmond?
戴斯蒙德
Desmond!
湯姆 住手
Tom. Stop.
不能這樣教孩子
What's that gonna teach the boy?
他已經夠暴力的了
He's violence enough already.
行吧 你就繼續寵著他吧
Okay, fine. You go smother him in kisses.
繼續告訴他 這世界是個美好善良的地方
You tell him the world is a soft and gentle place.
哈爾會沒事的
Hal's gonna be okay.
嘿
Hey.
我差點就殺了他
I could've killed him.
是的 是差點
Yes, you could have.
殺戮是最大的罪惡
Murder, it's the worst sin of all.
而奪走另一個人的生命
And to take another man's life,
在上帝眼中 是最嚴重的罪惡
that is the most egregious sin in Lord's eye.
這個最傷上帝的心
Nothing hurts His heart so much.
- 你聽不懂話嗎 - 湯姆 你...
- Don't you understand English? - God konw, Tom ...
- 難道還要我再說一次嗎 - 我告訴你...
- Do I have to tell you again? - I am telling you...
你最好自己滾 女人 否則我會給你點顏色看看
You move, woman, or I will wallop you good and hard!
到底怎麼回事
What the hell is going on?
- 你沒事吧 貝莎 - 你他媽管好自己吧
- You okay, Bertha?- You mind your own damned business!
回去睡覺吧 湯姆
Go sleep it off, Tom.
我討厭他
I hate him.
媽媽
Momma?
他為什麼這麼恨我們
Why does he hate us so much?
他不恨我們
Oh, he don't hate us.
他恨的是自己
He hates himself.
有時候
Sometimes.
今晚你父親... 這不是他本來的樣子
Your daddy tonight... that ain』t the real him.
我希望你們能像我一樣 認識戰前的他
I wish you knew him like I did, before the war.
我們唱得如何 戴斯蒙德
How do we sound, Desmond?
就像是天堂裏的天使 媽媽
Like a heavenly host angel, Mom.
你知道 說謊也是種罪
Now, you know it's a sin to tell a lie,
特別是在這裏
especially in this place.
我從來沒說過 那是負責歌唱的天使
Well, I never said they were singing angels.
外面發生了什麼 戴斯蒙德
What's going on out there, Desmond?
快 把車抬起來 把車抬起來
Go on. Get it up, get it up!
把他拉出來
Drag him out.
把墊子拉出來
Just the tarp.
我去叫救護車
I'll phone an ambulance.
不 沒時間了
No, no time.
約書亞 你的皮卡呢
Joshua, your pick-up?
快去
Quick!
好的
Okay.
- 你會沒事的 - 你會沒事的
- You're going to be fine now. - You're going to be fine.
有人在照顧你
You're in good hands.
他怎麼了
What have we got here?
主動脈破裂
That's a severed artery.
- 準備縫合 - 好的 醫生
- Get some sutures.- Yes, doctor.
壓住傷口
Put some pressure on it.
這根止血帶是你綁的嗎
Did you apply this tourniquet?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
幹得好 你也許救了這孩子的命
Nice work. You might've saved this boy's life.
有我們陪著你 你會沒事的
You're staying with us. You're going to be okay.
我們可以搞定
We can get that.
你叫什麼 孩子
What's your name, son?
吉爾伯特
Gilbert.
- 需要手術嗎 - 沒錯 需要手術
- Surgery? - Yeah, Surgery.
保持清醒 你會沒事的
Stay with us, you're gonna be okay.
你感覺疼嗎
You feel pain?
當然了 醫生
Certainly, doc.
保持清醒 好嗎
Stay with us, okay?
軍隊體測在那邊 這裏是獻血處
Army physical is that way. This is for giving blood.
你沒事吧
Are you alright?
沒事 那不是我的血
Oh no. That's not mine.
我沒事
I'm fine.
謝謝關心 女士
Thank you for asking, though, ma'am.
你需要什麼嗎
What do you need?
我的皮帶
My belt.
我借給出事的那個小伙子了
I lend it to the boy who had the accident.
沒有皮帶 我的褲子會往下掉
My pants don't hold up so good without it.
好吧 我沒有你的皮帶
Well, I don't have your belt.
不 我知道 女士
No. I know that, ma'am.
皮帶在外面 還在那個小伙子腿上
It's out there, right out there with the boy still.
好吧
Okay.
我只是在這裏負責采血
I'm just here to take blood.
我來獻血吧
I'll give you mine.
好吧
Okay,
去那間屋子裏 和其他人一起等著
go to that room over there and wait with the others.
我會叫你
I'll call you.
那個... 房間
That... that room.
你之前獻過血嗎
You've ever given blood before, Mr....
道斯
Doss.
但我的朋友都叫我戴斯蒙德
But my friends call me Desmond.
沒有 女士 這是第一次獻血
No, ma'am. My first time.
我的夢想是當一名醫生 但...
I always dream about being a doctor but...
我沒怎麼上過學
I didn't get much school.
獻完了血 你可能會有點頭暈
You might be a little dizzy when we're done.
有人會來接你嗎
Is somebody picking you up?
不 女士 我打算走回去
No, ma'am. Walking back.
你住在哪裏呢
Where do you live?
希爾堡 女士
Fort Hill, ma'am.
那很遠啊
That's a ways.
不遠 也就五六英里吧
No. Just five or six miles,
如果我從樹林走回去
but I cut through the woods.
那就是七英里
It's seven that way!
你肯定很喜歡樹林吧
You must really like the woods.
是的 女士 當然
Yes, ma'am. Sure do.
好吧
Okay.
用力按住這裏
Put some pressure here.
你沒事吧
You okay?
沒事
Yeah.
你穿得這麼帥 要去哪裏啊
Where are you going looking all spruced and nice?
昨天遇見了一個人
Met someone yesterday.
一個在醫院的護士
A nurse over at the hospital.
她叫多蘿西·舒特 我要娶她
Her name's Dorothy Schutte, and I'm gonna marry her.
天哪 她知道嗎
Goodness, does she know that?
還不知道 但她會知道的
Well, not yet. She's about to.
你和女人說過話嗎
You've ever even spoken to a woman?
我的意思是 除了家人以外的女人
I mean, one that's not family.
我和她說過話了
Spoke to her.
既然那樣 來和你哥哥抱一個
Well, in that case, come and give your brother a big hug.
- 來吧 - 不要用你的髒手碰我
- Come here. - Keep your greasy paws off me.
祝我好運 媽媽
Wish me luck, momma.
祝你好運
Good luck.
下一個
Next.
坐吧
Grab a seat.
您之前獻過血嗎
You've ever given blood before?
獻過 女士
Yes, ma'am. I have.
你是那個皮帶男孩
You're the belt man.
我叫戴斯蒙德 是的 女士
Desmond, yes, ma'am.
戴斯蒙德 你不能連著兩天來獻血
Well, Desmond, we can't take your blood two days in a row.
那好吧 我來是為了要回我的血
Well, that's good. I came to get mine back.
什麼
You what?
我的血 把它還給我
My blood, I need it back.
那樣可不行
Well, it don't work like that.
我們不能還給你
We can't just give it back to you.
你必須還給我
Well, you got to.
自從你用針頭紮了我之後
Ever since you stuck me with that needle,
我的心就跳得飛快
my heart has been beating real fast.
每次我想到你 就跳得更快了
Everytime I think about you, it beats faster still.
我從沒聽過這樣的搭訕
I never heard that one before.
陳腔濫調
It's pretty corny.
是嗎
It is?
沒錯
Yeah.
真可惜 我還練了整整一個晚上
That's a shame. I've done practicing that all night.
表現得不好嗎
No good?
我可沒那麼說
I didn't say that.
動脈和靜脈的區別是什麼
What's the difference between an artery and a vein?
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
那個男孩的事故
The boy's accident.
動脈的血是噴出來的
Arteries spurt blood.
靜脈呢
And veins?
流出來的
Bleed.
我覺得 你應該在出門前
I think you need to practice your
好好練習下 如何和女生聊天
boy-girl-dating-talk at home before you come out.
沒錯 我確實需要練習
Yeah, I probably do.
如果你感興趣 我可以給你一本書
I'll give you a book if you're that interested.
關於約會的嗎
On dating?
關於血液的
On blood.
還有什麼醫學問題嗎
Another medical question perhaps?
不 我覺得 你是我見過最漂亮的姑娘
No. I just think you're the prettiest thing I've ever seen.
因為我坐在暗處 你看不清楚
That's because I'm sitting in the dark.
不
No.
你真是太美了
You're just beautiful.
別擋道
Out of the way!
你走路得看著前面
You need to watch where you're going.
抱歉 我以為你不介意
I'm sorry. I didn't think you'd mind.
你又沒問
You didn't ask.
我以為你會接受
I thought you might've liked it.
你要是問了 我說不定會接受
Well, I might've if you'd asked.
你要來嗎
You coming?
走路看著點
Watch where you're walking!
為何你之前沒告訴我們
Why didn't you say nothing to us?
因為你們會盡力勸我不要去
'Cause you would've tried and talked me out of it.
而我知道自己這樣做才是對的
I know what I'm doing is right.
那聖經上說的十誡呢
And what about His commandment?
在戰爭中 殺戮不是罪惡
It's not killing in a war.
我是在幫助我們教堂裏的小伙子們 以免他們參戰
I was protecting loads of boys from our church from going.
好吧
Yeah.
現在是戰時 國家需要兵源
There's a war and they need men.
在造紙廠工作 並不會拯救這個國家
And working in a paper mill ain't going to save this country.
你看起來像個電影明星
Looks like a movie star,
小伙子
our boy.
軍服很帥
Nice uniform.
帽子也不錯
Good hat.
讓我想起 我們出征法國時
Reminds me of how Artie Giddens looked
亞提·吉登斯穿著那套軍服的樣子
in his look in his uniform when we went to France.
還記得他嗎 貝莎
Remember him, Bertha?
別這樣 湯姆
Don't, Tom.
怎麼了
What?
我只是想說 亞提裝著軍服真是精神
I'm just saying how snappy Artie looked in his uniform.
你們這些姑娘貌似都這麼覺得
All you girls certainly seemed to think so.
當時 他身邊圍的全是姑娘 他可驕傲了
He had them flocking to him. He was most proud.
我只希望 如果哈爾中彈
I just hope that when our Hal get shot,
子彈會從他夾克的前面穿過
it's through the front of his jacket.
那種乾脆的射入傷 不會弄得太難看
Like a simple entry wound, not much mess.
當初亞提是從背後被擊中
Artie got hit in the back, It blew most of his
內臟和腸子全從前面炸了出來 掉得滿地都是
guts and intestines out his front, awful everywhere.
完全把他的制服毀了
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
幸好他當時已經死了
It was lucky he was dead
永遠不會知道 他的軍服有多難看
so he never knew how awful his uniform looked.
你給我滾出去
Get out of my sight.
你到底是誰呀 難道是山羊嗎
What are you? Part mountain goat?
你還要不要幫我一把啊 戴斯蒙德·道斯
Are you gonna help me, Desmond Doss?
還是就這麼丟下我 困在這裏
Or are you just gonna leave me stranded?
我來幫你
I'll help you.
但你要答應一個條件
But it's gonna cost you.
什麼條件
What?
一個吻
A kiss.
這簡直就是赤裸裸的敲詐
That is pure blackmail.
是的 女士 沒錯
Well yes, ma'am it is,
不過我依然堅持我的要求
but that is still my condition.
那就說定了
That's the deal.
我會把你帶上去
And I'm going to hold you to it.
等等
Well, hold on now.
你不會再扇我耳光了吧
You ain't gonna slap me, are you?
因為要是我跌下去 我會把你也拽下去的
'Cause I'll fall off, I'm gonna take you with me.
那就吻我試試看吧
Kiss me and find out.
怎麼了
What?
我必須去參軍了
I have to enlist.
我不能待在後方 讓他們為我拚命
I can't stay here while all them go fight for me.
你可以的
Yes, you can.
- 你可以待在這裏 - 多蘿西 我必須去
- You can stay here. - Dorothy, I have to.
我想去做醫護兵
I want to be a medic.
我覺得我可以去救人 而不是去殺人
I figure I'll be saving people, not killing them.
我得去上班了 我快要遲到了
I have to go to work. I'm going to be late.
多蘿西 親愛的
Dorothy, darling.
多蘿西 多蘿西
Dorothy. Dorothy.
所以你是要向我求婚 還是怎麼呢
So are you gonna ask me to marry you or what?
我不知道啊 你會答應我嗎
Well, I don't know. You're still going to have me?
我也不知道 你還沒問呢
Well, I wouldn't know, you haven't asked.
那我這就求婚
Well, I'm asking you,
真心誠意
with all my heart and then some.
你願意嫁給我嗎
Will you marry me?
那我就答應吧
Then, yes.
我願意
Yes. I will.
什麼時候呢
When?
等到你第一次休假回家 我們就結婚
Soon as you get your first leave.
不過現在 我還是不喜歡你
But I still don't like you at this moment.
好吧
Yeah.
Okay.
我愛你
Okay. Well, I love you.
噓
Shhhh.
媽媽說 在這裏可以找到你
Momma said come see you here.
當初 他們三個是我最好的朋友
These three were my best friends.
我和他們一起長大
I grew up with 'em.
和他們一起闖禍 和他們一起追女孩
I got into trouble with 'em. Chased girls with 'em.
然後也和他們一起入伍
And I enlisted with 'em.
現在 我的朋友們就在這裏
Now my friends are there,
被泥土和野草覆蓋 被蟲子吞噬
covered in dirt and grasss, and eaten by worms.
我不想也來這裏祭奠我的兒子們
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
爸爸 我已經報名了
Daddy, I... I signed up already.
我別無選擇啊 老爹
I couldn't do otherwise, pop.
- 其他人都... - 你不是其他人
- Everybody else is doing...- You ain't everybody else!
其他人都不加思考
Everybody else jumps in and does thing quick,
魯莽行事
without thinking!
就像我們當初那樣 都是白癡
Like the damn idiot fools we were.
你要明白 那些能活下來的士兵
You know what? Soldiers who live,
是因為他們有能力活下來
they live cause they can do that!
而你不行
You can't!
你得冷靜下來
Look, you gotta sit
好好思考 好好祈禱
and think and pray about everything.
瞧瞧你 你現在就做得很好
I mean, look at you, you're doing it right now
如果你去了 你根本就活不下去
You won't be able to live with yourself if you go.
不 如果我不去 我才活不下去
No, I won't be able to live with myself if I don't.
我要去當醫護兵
I'm going to be a medic.
我要以這種方式服役
That's going to be my way to serve.
看來你都想明白了啊
See, there you go, thinking it all out.
怎麼著 你覺得這場戰爭會配合你嗎
What, you figure this war is going to fit in with you?
配合你的想法嗎
Your ideas?
我毫不懷疑 這肯定會非常艱難
Well, I don't doubt it's going to be hard.
不是艱難 而是根本就不可能
It won't be hard. It will be impossible.
你知道嗎
You know, whatever
不管你那瘋狂的腦子裏 現在有什麼想法
beliefs you have in your crazy head now,
戰爭都不會按你想的發展
they won't ever play out it.
戰爭從來都不是那樣的
It don't work that way.
如果真有奇跡出現
And if by some, I don't know,
你能活下來
miracle chance you survive,
你也應該感謝上帝
you won't be giving no thanks to God.
- 準備好了嗎 - 好了
- Ready? - Ready.
我們需要新鮮空氣
We all need some air.
來吧 夥計們 快點吧 為國效力吧
C'mon fellas, shake a leg. Uncle Sam's got you now.
跟媽媽說再見吧
Say goodbye to Momma.
快點啊
C'mon.
女士們 請遠離大巴
Ladies, please! Step away from the bus.
我差點忘了
I almost forgot.
我需要把撬棍 才能把你們分開嗎
Do I need a crowbar?
給你
Here.
我想要你帶上這個
I want you to have this.
這是我的
It's mine.
你隨身帶著它
You keep it right here,
就像我也在你身旁
where I'll be.
再見
Bye.
我愛你
I love you.
不許那樣說我女人
Hey, don't say that about my girl.
不好意思 兄弟
Hey. Sorry, pal.
這意味著 你就是那個傢伙
Means you're the person.
我這裏挨了一拳
I got a punch here.
不 只是被撞了下
Nah, it's just a bump.
難不成我每次走向自己的床位
Do I have to gaze at your deformity
還要盯著你那玩意看嗎
everytime I walk to my bed?
看吧 看吧 你就嫉妒吧 朋友
Gaze upon it in envy, my friend.
你還好嗎
You okay there?
你看起來是迷路了
You look lost.
這裏有個空床
Vacancy right here.
明智的選擇
Wise choice.
這可是依山傍水的好位置
It's got views of the mountains down to lake.
我是蘭德爾·富勒
Randall Fuller.
我是戴斯蒙德·道斯
Desmond Doss.
叫他"老師"吧
Call him 'Teach'.
他說的話 別人都聽不懂
No one understand a word he says.
那是因為這裏其他人都不讀書
That's because no one else here can read.
不過那對蛋蛋的主人
The testicles there belong to a man
自稱為"大明星"
calling himself 'Hollywood'.
那玩意看上去 像是屬於塊頭更小的傢伙
You know, they look like they belong to a smaller guy.
你很瞭解蛋蛋嘛
You know testicles.
嘿
Oh hey,
這可是我剛領的鞋
I just got this shoes.
嘿
Hey ya.
我是來自紅杉的格雷斯·諾蘭 你從哪裏來的
Grease Nolan out of Redwood. Where you from?
- 弗吉尼亞 - 鄉巴佬 是嗎
- Virginia.- Hillbilly? huh?
你娶了你的親表妹嗎
You marry your first cousin?
開個玩笑
I'm just joking.
那邊是史密提 正在教訓科幸斯基
That Smitty over there, whipping Kirzinski's ass.
難道你能做的比我更好嗎 傻瓜
Like you were doing any better, chowderhead.
嘿 我是不想讓你難堪
Hey, I didn't want to embarass you.
我是沃爾·科幸斯基 幸會
Wal Kirzinski, nice to meet you.
嘿 瘦高個
Hey, beanpole,
你剛才說自己叫什麼來著
what did you say your name was?
戴斯蒙德·道斯
Desmond Doss.
那邊是特克斯·路易斯
That's Tex Lewis over there,
自以為自己是牛仔
he thinks he some kind of cowbow.
還有維托·瓦拉利
And Vito Rinnelli.
塊頭挺小 不過很兇悍
Now he maybe small, but he is a bulldog.
- 你好 - 我是戴斯蒙德
- How you doing? - Desmond.
這位帥小伙叫納吉·福特
This handsome guy right here is Lucky Ford.
那邊是沃克和潘尼克
That's Walker and Pinnick over there,
假裝自己是玩牌高手
pretending they're card shufflers.
格雷斯 安靜點 好嗎
Pipe down, Grease, alright?
別光說 有本事拿錢過來玩
Unless you want to put your money where your mouth is.
這是聖經 對嗎
Hey, the old good book, right?
我記得
I think...
我記得納吉也有本"聖經"
I think Lucky's got a good book.
是吧 納吉
Right, Lucky?
挺好看的
It's a good read.
集合
Attention!
列隊 快點
Line up! Move it!
快點 快點
Let's go. Move it. Move it.
你這人看起來長得真奇怪
You're a very strange-looking individual
如果你不介意我這麼說的話 二等兵
if you don't mind me saying so, Private.
姓名
Name?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
你死了多久了 孩子
How long have you been dead, son?
長官您說什麼
Sir?
我不是"長官"
I am not "Sir"!
叫我豪威爾中士 或者中士
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge.
只有無用之人 才會自稱長官
"Sir" you save for useless people.
你就叫鬼二吧
The name is "Ghoul," you say?
我叫沃克
Walker.
中士
Sergeant!
就叫鬼二
Ghoul it is.
是 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
你的表現有點不對勁啊啊 二等兵
There's something off in your presentation, Private.
說不清道不明
Can't place it.
是你的頭髮嗎
Is it your hair?
還是你褲子上的褶皺呢
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
我的腳上插著把刀 中士
I have a knife in my foot, Sergeant.
對哦 當然了 就是這把刀
Yes, of course. That's it. The knife..
你叫什麼名字 士兵
What is your name, soldier?
史密提·瑞克
Smitty Riker.
不 你的名字是白癡二等兵
No. Your name is Private Idiot.
你知道為什麼嗎
Do you know why?
因為我腳上插著把刀
'Cause I have a knife in my foot.
誰把刀插在那裏的 二等兵
Who placed the knife there, Private?
那只是場意外 中士 我們鬧著玩呢
It was an accident, Sergeant. I was playing stretch.
居然不是你自己有意插上去的
I'm heartened by the knowledge
這簡直太讓我高興了
you did not place it there with intention.
誰扔的這把刀
Who threw the knife?
是我 中士
I did, Sergeant.
二等兵科幸斯基
Private Kirzinski.
你看起來像印第安人
You look part Indian.
你屬於哪個部落的啊 孩子
To what tribe do you belong, son?
不知道 我是波蘭人
Don't know. I'm polish.
錯了
Wrong.
我相信
I believe
你肯定有切羅基族或者肖尼族血統
you must have Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
- 不是的 中士 - 你是在反駁我嗎
- No, Sergeant.- Are you contradicting me?
你這個印第安混蛋
You wagon-burning son of a bitch?
不 中士
No, Sergeant!
讓我看看你印第安人的作戰口號吧 孩子
Let me see your Indian war cry, son.
我不...
I... I don't...
大聲點 讓我看看
Louder! Let me see it.
你的動物天性是什麼
What is your animal spirit?
- 你是束帶蛇嗎 - 不是 中士
- Are you a Garter Snake?- No, Sergeant!
- 你是花栗鼠嗎 - 不是 中士
- Are you a chipmunk? -No, Sergeant!
- 你是跳舞的馴鹿嗎 - 不是 中士
- Are you a dancing reindeer? - No, Sergeant!
- 你是在反駁我嗎 - 不是 中士
- Are you contradicting me, Private? - No, Sergeant!
很好
Good.
那這樣 從此以後我就叫你"酋長"了
Then I shall henceforth call you "Chief"
來表達對你族人的尊敬之情
as a sign of great respect to your people.
謝謝 中士
Thank you, Sergeant!
你是在嘲笑我嗎
Are you grinning at me, boy,
還是說你平時就這樣
or is that your natural state?
不是的 中士
No, Sergeant.
姓名 二等兵
Name, private?
戴斯蒙德·道斯
Desmond Doss.
那些玉米桿 都比你體格強壯
I have seen stalks of corn with better physiques.
讓人想要把你耳朵揪下來 二等兵
Makes me want to pull an ear off, Private.
你能背動與自己身體等重的東西嗎
Can you carry your weight?
可以 中士
Yes, Sergeant!
對你而言 應該是輕而易舉
Should be easy for you, then
- 下士 - 在 中士
- Corporal. - Sergeant?
小心不要讓這孩子 被大風刮走了
Make sure you keep this man away from strong winds.
遵命 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
- 白癡二等兵 - 在 中士
- Private idiot.- Yes, Sergeant.
抬腳
Raise your foot.
再抬高點
Higher.
全體都有 出去訓練
Everyone outside now.
出去
Move it.
我說了 出去
I said move it.
好的 我穿好制服就出去 中士
All right. Just getting in my uniform, Sarge.
我有叫他穿制服嗎 下士
Did I ask him to, Corporal?
我不記得你說過這話 中士
No memory of it, Sarge.
我相信
I believe any man
既然你對自己的裸體如此滿意
who takes such pride in his natural naked state
那你肯定也樂意在大庭廣眾下 好好炫耀
will surely enjoy the brisk of the outdoors.
立刻給我出去  "那話兒"大兵
Now move your privates, Private Parts.
快出去
Move it.
真是個暴露狂
You son of an exhibitionist.
接下來 我會教你們怎麼打單套結
I'm gonna teach you how to tie a bowline knot.
當我把你們這些混小子從高處踢下來時
So you can get your sorry asses down from a height,
它能幫你安全降落
so I may then kick them!
先繞一個圈
Create a loop.
當它是兔洞
This is the rabbit hole.
兔子從洞裏鑽出來
The rabbit comes out of his hole,
繞著樹跑圈
runs around the tree,
再回到兔洞裏
goes back into the hole.
好了
Alright.
你們試試
Let's go.
打得很不錯 牛仔
Very good, Tex.
繼續掙扎吧 老師
Keep struggling, Teach.
你以前套過羊嗎 大明星
Have you ever roped a goat, Hollywood?
沒有 中士
No, Sarge.
那你直視過羊的眼睛嗎
Have you ever looked into a goat's eyes.
沒有 中士
No, Sarge.
很好 否則那就太變態了
Good, that would be unnatural.
你知道 如果不呼吸 你真的會死噢
You know if you don't breath, you'll die.
做得不錯 白癡二等兵
Good, Private Idiot.
恭喜你 胖球
Congratulations, Greaseball,
你剛從五十英尺高的地方墜落 還摔斷了脖子
you just fell fifty feet and broke your neck.
厲害啊
Brialliant,
維托·瓦拉利二等兵
Private Vito Rinnelli.
你把自己勒死了 呆瓜
You strangled yourself, numbnuts.
你喜歡貝尼托嗎
Are you a fan of Benito?
- 不喜歡 中士 - 那就再長高點
- No, Sergeant. - A bit taller.
如果你是美國人 就再長高點
If you were American, you'd be taller.
道斯 瞧瞧你做了什麼
What've we got here, Doss,
正好一個配一個
One for each titty?
小子 你是在打單套結
You're tying a bowline, boy,
不是做內衣
not building a bra!
有什麼好笑的呢 下士
What is so funny, Corporal?
我也不知道 中士
Couldn't tell you, Sergeant.
快點
Come on.
快啊 姑娘們 加把勁
Come on, ladies. Pick it up.
快動起來 動起來
Move it. Move it.
我要看到你們的熱情
I wanna see some fire here.
看到你們的鬥志
A little hustle.
拿出點本事來
Show me something.
給我認真地跑
Run like you mean it!
下來 下來 加快速度
Down. Down. Down. Faster, faster!
快點 來吧 快 快
Move it. Come on. Move it. Move it.
來吧 好好地洗個澡吧 小子們
Let's go, it's bath time, boys!
好好地洗個澡
It's bath time!
快 快 動起來
Move. Move. Move.
讓我看看你們的本事
I want to see you work.
快 進去 都進去
Let's go. Dig, dig, dig!
別怕髒 速度快 快點
Don't forget behind your ears. Let's go. Move!
你一定很享受這過程吧 變態暴露狂
I bet you're enjoying this, you naked degenerate.
快 動作快 快
Let's go. Hustle. Hustle. Hustle.
快跑
Move.
快跑 還等什麼呢 動作快點
Let's go. What are we waiting on? Let's go.
快跑
Move your ass.
到木板那去 到木牆那去 不准放棄
Get the wood! Get the wood! Don't get splinters!
沖 衝啊
Drive! Drive!
- 天 你還好嗎 - 沒事
- Jesus, are you okay? - Yeah, I'm fine.
快點
Move!
都精神點 小伙子們 動作快
Spirit here, boys. Move!
加油 快跑
Come on. Move!
你們在幹嘛呢
What the hell is wrong with you?
沒人說可以休息
No one said take a rest!
快給我跑到終點線去 快 快
Move your asses to the finish line. Move! Move!
衝刺 衝刺
Hustle! Hustle!
跑過終點線
Get your asses across the damn line.
對 幹得不錯 道斯
Aye, nice work, Doss.
這些是美國政府
This is a personal gift from
為在場各位準備的禮物
the United States Government to each and everyone of you.
美國軍用步槍
A standard issue U.S. Rifle.
口徑7.62毫米
Caliber 30.
M1加蘭德步槍
M1
這是一款自動上膛
a clip-fed, shoulder-fired,
半自動肩扛式武器
semi-automatic weapon designed
能夠為敵人帶去滅頂之災
to bring death and destruction to the enemy.
她就是你的愛人
This is to be your lover,
你的心肝
your mistress,
你的寶貝
your concubine.
也可以說是
Perhaps,
你這輩子唯一的真愛
the only thing in life you'll ever truly love.
各位 舞會開始了
Fellas, let's dance.
每人挑個姑娘吧
Grab a girl.
別把你們的槍朝前
Don't point your gun forward.
我可不想今天被射中
I do not want to be shot today.
雖然我知道 你們很想那樣做
No matter how much you are tempted.
把槍放到你們身旁
Place the weapon by your side.
立正
Pay attention.
有問題嗎 玉米稈二等兵
Problem, Private Corn Stalk?
你不喜歡這槍的尺寸
Is there not one in your size,
還是不喜歡這槍的顏色呢
or is it the color that is the issue?
沒有 中士
No, Sarge.
有人跟我說 我可以不用帶武器
I was... I was told I don't have to carry a weapon.
再說一次 上前一步 二等兵
Come again, step forward, Private.
我剛才肯定是聽錯了
I can't be hearing this right.
我很抱歉 中士
Well, I'm sorry, Sergeant.
我不能碰槍
I can't touch a gun.
所以 到底出什麼問題了
What exactly is the problem?
沒什麼問題 只是個誤會 長官
No problem, just a mistake, sir.
我報名參軍時 已經和陸軍說過...
I... I told the Army when I joined up...
那不可能
That's not possible.
你知道為什麼不可能嗎 二等兵
Do you know why it's not possible, Private?
不知道 長官
No, sir.
因為美國陸軍是不會出錯的
'Cause the United States Army does not make mistakes.
所以 如果有問題
So if there's a problem,
那肯定就是你的問題
you must be that problem.
我本不該被編入步兵連
I was just never supposed to be sent to a rifle company.
他是個拒絕服兵役者 長官
He's a CO, sir.
你是個拒絕服兵役者
You're a conscientious objector,
- 那你還來參軍 - 你誤會了 長官
- and you joined the army? - Well no, sir.
我只是堅持反對暴力而已
I'm... I'm a conscientious cooperator.
你是在耍我嗎 道斯
Are you screwing with me, Doss?
我沒有 長官 我是自願參軍
No. No, sir. I volunteered.
不管是穿軍服 敬禮
I got no... no problem with wearing my uniform,
還是盡我的職責 我都沒問題
or saluting the flag and... and doing my duty.
只是 持槍殺人 是絕對不行的
It's just... just carrying a gun and taking a human life.
你不殺生 是這個意思嗎
You don't kill. That's all?
是的 長官 是這個意思
Yes, sir. That's all.
你知道戰場上 幹的就是殺人勾當嗎
You know quite a bit of killing does occur in a war.
我知道 長官
Yes, Sir.
殺戮就是戰爭的本質
I mean that is the essential nature of war.
是的 長官
Yes, sir.
好吧
Alright.
那你對美國陸軍還有什麼其他要求嗎
Do you have any other requirements of the United States army?
為了能讓您在這裏 和我們一起生活得舒心
Is there anything else that we can do to ensure
還有什麼我們能為您做的嗎
that you have a comfortable stay here with us?
他不想在週六執勤 長官
He doesn't wanna work on Saturday, sir.
週六是... 我信奉安息日會
Well, Saturday is... I'm a Seventh Day Adventist.
週六是安息日 所以
So... saturday is my sabbath, so...
我不能工作
I'm not allowed to work then.
在我看來 這完全不成問題
I don't think that poses a problem,
你覺得呢 中士
do you, Sergeant?
考慮到道斯二等兵是個虔誠的信徒
We should simply ask the enemy not to invade on the Sabbath,
我們應該通知敵人 讓他們別在週六發動進攻
'cause Private Doss here is a prayer.
好了 事情已經很清楚了
Alright. Now we got that clear.
現在 我來跟你說說我的要求吧
Now let me tell you my requirements.
不像你的要求那麼複雜
They're not as complicated as yours.
我的要求很簡單
They are very simple.
只要你還在這個軍營 只要你還是我的兵
As long as you're in this company under my command,
你就得遵守我的命令 完畢
you will obey my orders. Period.
如果在這裏 你都不能服從命令
If you can't do it here,
那麼在戰場上 我就更不能信任你
I can't trust you to do it in the battle.
我會用第八條例來處理你
I'm putting you in
以精神問題為理由 遣送你回去
for a Section 8, psychiatric discharge.
解散
Dismissed.
各位
Gentlemen!
我想向你們介紹一下 戴斯蒙德·道斯二等兵
I want you to meet Private Desmond Doss.
顯而易見
Apparently,
道斯二等兵反對暴力
Private Doss does not believe in violence.
他絕不會採取暴力行動
He does not practice violence.
甚至不會屈尊去碰武器
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
道斯二等兵
You see, Private Doss
是一位拒絕服兵役者
is a conscientious objector.
在此 我請求各位
So I plead with you,
在戰場上 就別指望他來救你們了
do not look to him to save you on the battlefield,
因為他肯定會
because he will undoubtedly
忙著和他的良心作鬥爭 根本沒時間理你們
be too busy wrestling with his conscience to assist.
中士 不是這樣的 中士
Sarge, that's not true, Sarge.
二等兵 別說話
Private, as you were.
我知道
Now, I realize
各位對這件事一定有所怨言
some of you might have strong feelings about this.
我們浴血奮戰
It is what we men fight for.
就是為了捍衛我們的權利
To defend our rights,
保護我們的女人和孩子
and to protect our women and children.
哪怕道斯二等兵的信仰
Even if Private Doss's belief
會對婦女兒童造成傷害
might cause women and children to die.
在此 我希望連隊的每一位
So I will expect everyone in this company
能夠給予道斯二等兵應得的尊敬
to give Private Doss the full measure of respect he is due
畢竟他在這裏也待不久了
for the short time he will be with us.
明白了嗎
Am I clear?
是 中士
Yes, sergeant.
你看什麼呢 小妹妹
What'cha got there, Dessie?
你知道那是什麼嗎
You know what that is?
這個版本有點小啊
It just seems kind of small.
這本小聖經正適合你這個小男生
It's half-the-Bible for half-the-man.
拜託 史密提 把他的聖經還他吧
For Pete's sake, Smitty give him back his Bible.
我可沒跟你說話
I don't remember speaking to you.
你為什麼不動手呢
So, how come you don't fight?
你是不屑跟我們動手嗎
You think you better than us?
不是
No.
那如果你被打了呢
Well, what if you're attacked?
例如 就像這樣
Say, like that.
聖經告訴你
The Bible says
把另一側臉也湊過來 不是嗎
to turn your other cheekbone, don't it?
各位 我覺得這不是宗教信仰問題
See, I don't think this is a question of religion, fellas.
我覺得這就是懦弱
I think this is cowardice,
顯而易見
plain and simple.
你還好嗎 道斯
You alright, Doss?
你就是孬種 對嗎
Are you chickenshit, that it?
來啊
Go on.
打我一拳
Take a poke.
告訴你 我讓你隨便打
Tell you what, I'm gonna give a free shot.
打這裏
Right there.
打我啊 道斯
Hit me, Doss.
來啊
Go on.
揍他
Let him have it!
上啊
Go ahead.
不出手嗎
No?
孬種
Chickenshit.
- 這是什麼 - 還給我
- What is this? - Give me that.
這姑娘真水靈
This is a fine looking broad.
真漂亮
Nice.
傳過來看看
Hey, pass it around.
只有真正的英雄才配得上
Now, this would be the kind of broad
這樣的美人
that deserves a real man.
把照片還給我
Give me that back.
求我
Please.
求你
"求你 史密提 把照片還給我"
"Please give it back, Smitty."
求你 史密提 把照片還給我
Please give it back, Smitty.
你有出現幻聽嗎 戴斯蒙德
Do you hear voices, Desmond?
沒有 長官
No, sir.
根據我的理解 上帝會跟你說話
But I understand that God talks to you.
對嗎
Is that right?
長官 我並不是個瘋子
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
那大家都認為你瘋了
Then how you feel... most people regard you,
你有什麼感受呢
a... a crazy person?
我知道我和大家不一樣 但...
I'm... I'm different. I know that. But...
我沒打算強迫自己裝得和大家一樣
I'm not gonna pretend to be something I'm not.
我就是我
I am what I am.
聽起來很孤獨啊
Sounds lonely.
你孤獨嗎
Are you lonely?
所以你沒有出現幻聽 是嗎
So, you don't hear voices?
沒有 長官
No, sir.
我向上帝祈禱
I pray to God
希望他能聽見
and I like to think He hears me,
但我並沒有和他聊天
but it ain't a conversation,
並非像我們正在假裝的這樣
like the one we're pretending to have right now.
假裝嗎 二等兵
Pretending, Private?
是的 長官 我知道你想...
Well, yes, sir. I know what you really wanna do is...
想用第八條例把我趕出軍隊
is give me a section 8, draw me out of the Army.
但我沒瘋
But... I'm not off...
我腦子沒問題
Up above.
我只是堅守我的信仰而已
I just simply believe what I believe.
我在盡量試圖理解你 好嗎
Well, I'm trying to understand, alright?
是上帝告訴你 不要拿槍的嗎
Was it...  Was it God who told you not to pick up a rifle?
上帝說 不要殺戮
God says not to kill.
那是十誡中最重要的一條
That's one of His most important commandments.
但大家都將其理解為 "不蓄意謀殺他人"
Most people take that to mean, "Don't commit murder."
戰爭 則是特殊情況
War is completely differen set of circumstances.
主說 "我賜給你們一條新的誡律
Jesus said "A new commandment I give unto you,
乃是叫你們彼此相愛
That you love one another,
如同我愛你一般"
just as I have loved you."
我們面對的可是惡魔撒旦本人
This is satan himself we're fighting.
作為一名虔誠的基督教徒 你應該能明白
Surely, as good Christian, you can see that.
我明白 長官 所以我才來參軍了
I can see that, sir, and that is why I joined up.
但很抱歉 我不會碰任何武器的
But I'm sorry, I will not bear arms.
毫無疑問 他的信仰非常獨特
His religious view is certainly unique,
但並不合適採用條例第八章
but they do not constitute grounds
沒法把他趕出軍隊
for Section 8 discharge.
有他這樣的人
How am I supposed to
在我隊伍裏 我要如何才能維持秩序呢
maintain discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我不知道
I don't know.
在我隊伍裏 我要如何才能維持秩序呢
maintain discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他出於信仰而拒絕服兵役 是合法的
But he is a legitimate conscientious objector,
只要能完成所有訓練內容
and he must be allowed to work as combat medic,
他就能以醫護兵的身份 留在軍隊裏
provided he qualifies in all other areas in his training.
或許我們可以幫助他 改變其想法
Perhaps we could help make believe in his idea.
沒錯 你讓他只負責營房和廚房的雜事
Yeah, you restrict him to barracks in KP.
他只要跟你說起上帝 你就給他點顏色看看
If he throws God at you, you throw hell right at him.
我要他走
I want him gone.
道斯 你的床太亂了
Doss, your area is in disgrace.
簡直就像個豬窩
It's a pig stock.
- 有什麼好笑的嗎 雷克 - 沒有 中士
- Something funny, Ryker? - No, Sarge!
- 你腦子有毛病嗎 - 沒有 中士
- You got some shit on your mind? - No, Sarge!
你們沒有意識到的
What you men fail to recognize
團隊中最弱者的能力 才真正決定團隊的水平
is a unit is no better than its weakest member.
為了幫助你們學習這個道理
Now, to help you learn that lesson,
這個週末 所有人都不許外出
there will be no passes this weekend.
全都滾到廚房去幫忙
You will all be on KP.
現在 所有人全副武裝 二十英里的負重越野
Right now everybody on full gear for 20-mile hike.
快點
Let's go.
出發
保持清醒
Get your heads right.
不要自怨自艾
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
看到你們自怨自艾的樣子 我就覺得噁心
Makes me sick seeing you feel sorry for yourself.
你們根本就不知道什麼是累
You dogs don't know what tired is.
我不停下 你們都別想休息
We gonna keep going till I drop.
來吧 夥計們
Come on, guys.
別打了 別打了
Hey, knock it off. Knock it off!
我還要睡覺呢
Trying to sleep here.
別碰我 別碰我
Get off me. Get off me.
你他媽到底為什麼還賴著不走呢
Why the hell are you still here?
- 立正 - 稍息
- Ten-hut.- As you were.
道斯呢
Where's Doss?
這對任何人都沒有好處
This isn't good for anybody.
這確實不是我當初報名參軍的原因
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
這跟你參軍的原因沒關係
It's not about what you joined up for.
而是關乎這裏所有人的性命
It's about the lives of every men in here.
還有你的性命 小子
And yours, son.
是時候退出了
It's time you quit this.
穿好衣服 我送你出去
Finish getting dress and I'll walk you down.
沒事的 道斯
It's okay, Doss.
沒什麼好羞恥的
There's no shame in this.
走吧
Let's go.
我今天還要值班
I got an extra guard duty today,
早上還要去廚房幫忙 所以...
and I'm on KP this morning, so...
走不了
I can't.
好吧 道斯
Alright, Doss.
道斯二等兵
Private Doss,
你能認出打你的人嗎
can you identify the men that beat you?
不 中士
No, Sarge.
你是說 你不知道誰打了你嗎
Are you saying that you don't know who attacked you?
我沒說我被打了啊 中士
I never said I was attacked, Sarge.
你到底在說什麼呢 道斯
Well, what the hell are you saying, Doss?
你睡覺睡得遍體鱗傷的嗎
You bruised half your body sleeping?
我睡相確實很差
I... I sleep pretty hard.
好吧
Alright.
如果這個週末 你們打算要享受艷福
If you plan on getting wet this weekend,
- 要記得做安全措施噢  -下一個
- make sure you put on a hat. - Next!
我可不想看你們帶著一身騷味回來
I don't want anyone coming back pissing cream.
難道你不想享受享受嗎 中士
What, you don't want to none for your coffee, Sarge?
那現在就來一發吧 史密提
How about a shot right now, Smitty?
- 這是你的經驗之談嗎 中士 - 下一個
- You speaking from experience, Sarge? - Next.
你去問問你媽就知道了 胖球
You'd have to ask your mom about that, greaseball.
敬禮
Move!
稍息
At ease.
道斯二等兵
Private Doss,
恐怕我不能批准你外出
I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
只有通過所有基礎訓練項目 才能享有假期
This is a furlough for men who had pass the basic training.
恕我直言 長官 我已經通過了
Well, sir... respectfully, sir, I have.
我三周前就開始申請這次外出了
I... I put in for this furlough three weeks ago.
今天下午 我就要結婚了
I'm getting married this afternoon.
上面寫著 你沒有通過步槍測試
It says you're not rifle-qualified.
但我不需要佩槍 長官
Well, I'm not required to carry a rifle, sir.
上校... 施特爾策上校 他...
Colonel... Colonel Stelzer he...
施特爾策上校的規矩是說
Colonel Stelzer's determination was...
"如果道斯想要留在軍隊 做醫護兵
"Doss must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
他必須通過所有的訓練測試"
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training."
但你並沒有通過步槍訓練 二等兵
And you have not qualifiedon the rifle range, private.
非常清楚
Pretty clear.
讓我看看 你會不會拿槍
Show me you know how to handle a rifle,
如果你會 我就批准你外出
and I'll sign your furlough.
- 坎農下士 - 長官
- Corporal Cannon. - Sir.
把你的佩槍遞給道斯二等兵
Hand private Doss your firearm.
我不會碰槍的 長官
I won't touch a rifle, sir.
我沒有在詢問你的意見 二等兵
I'm not asking you, Private.
這是指揮官給你下達的直接指令
That is a direct order from a company commander.
看在上帝的份上 道斯
For God's sake, Doss,
別胡鬧了 退出吧
you stop this nonsense and quit.
如果你拒絕
Refuse,
那我就只能把你送上軍事法庭了
and I will have no recourse but to court martial you,
在整個戰爭期間
and you will spend
你都將只能待在軍事監獄裏
the duration of the war in a military prison.
我做不到 長官
I can't, sir.
你還想等多久 多蘿西
How much longer would you like to wait, Dorothy?
我想 我們已經等得夠久了
I think it's been long enough.
很抱歉
I'm so very sorry.
有時候男人就會臨陣退縮
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
有些男人可能會吧
Some men might.
但我的戴斯蒙德不會
Not my Desmond.
你可能認為 我就是個混蛋
You probably think I'm a really son of a bitch
只在乎規定 而不愛惜自己手下
who cares only about regulations and not his men.
我可以看一下嗎
May I?
我和其他人一樣 也對聖經深信不疑
I believe in this book as much as any men.
也和其他人一樣
And just like any man,
良心備受煎熬
I wrestled with my conscience,
但當這世上你所珍視的一切
but what do you do
都受到攻擊時 你該怎麼辦
when everything you value in this world is under attacked?
我不知道 長官
I don't know, sir.
我不能回答如此深刻的問題
I ain't got answers to questions that big,
但我也感覺到 我的價值觀正受到衝擊
but I also feel like my values are under attack,
我甚至都不知道為什麼
and I don't know why.
我可不在乎你那什麼鬼原則
I don't give a rat-ass
因為日本人也不會在乎
about your principles because the Japs don't.
如果敵人襲擊你
If one of them attacks you
和其他受傷的士兵 你該怎麼辦
and some wounded soldier, what are you gonna do?
用聖經打他嗎
Hit him with your Bible?
我願意為我的隊友 獻出生命
I'm prepared to give my life for my men.
光靠犧牲自己的生命 並不能贏得戰爭
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
聽著
Look.
我來這裏
I'm only here because
是因為 我不想看到你被困在監獄裏
I don't wanna see you rotting in a prison cell.
認罪吧
Plead guilty,
在法庭上 請求他們的寬恕
throw yourself at the mercy of the court.
或許他們會讓你安然無恙地回家
Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
讓那些勇敢的人 去贏得這場戰爭吧
Let the brave men out there go and win this war.
如果我說服不了你 或許她可以
If I can't convinceyou, maybe she can.
他們不讓我打電話給你
They wouldn't let me call you.
我就知道這不是你的錯
I knew it wasn't your making.
他們對你幹了什麼
What've they done to you?
沒事 我沒事
It's okay. I'm alright.
我只是跟牆打了幾個回合 然後輸了而已
I just went a couple of rounds with the wall and lost.
他們說你很可能被送進監獄 戴斯蒙德
They're saying you could go to prison, Desmond.
利文沃斯堡監獄
Leavenworth.
肯定還有其他辦法
There must be some other way.
我不知道還能怎麼辦
I don't know what that could be.
除了碰槍這件事
I've done everything they asked me
他們說的我全照做了
except this one thing,
就因為我不肯殺人
and I'm being treated like a criminal
他們就如同對待犯人般對待我
just 'cause I won't kill.
你盡力了
You tried.
沒人能否認這一點
Nobody can say you didn't.
但你在監獄裏 能救到誰呢
But who are you gonna save in prison?
估計誰也救不了吧
Probably nobody.
那你為什麼 就不能拿起那該死的槍
Then why can't you just pick up the stupid gun
隨便裝裝樣子呢
and wave it around.
你不需要用它 只要做出讓步就好了
You don't have to use it, just meet them halfway.
但我做不到
But I can't do that.
你可以的 你只是太驕傲了
Yes, you can. It's just pride.
驕傲又頑固
Pride and stuborness.
不要混淆你的意志和主的意志
Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
我很驕傲嗎
Have I been prideful?
或許我確實很驕傲
Maybe I am prideful.
但如果不堅持我自己的信仰
But I don't know how I'm going to live with myself
我都不知道 該怎樣生活下去
if I don't stay true to what I believe.
更重要的是 該怎樣和你一起生活
much less how you could live with me.
我永遠不會成為 你眼中真正的男人
I'd never be the man that I want to be in your eyes.
我之所以愛你
I fell in love with you
因為你跟其他人不一樣
because you weren't like anyone else.
而你也不曾改變自己
and you didn't try to be.
永遠不要覺得 你會讓我失望
Do not think for one moment that you'll disappoint me.
無論怎樣
I will love you,
我都愛你
no matter what.
我不知道他要怎麼辦
I don't know what he's gonna do.
不管怎樣 他都會輸
He loses no matter what.
他們想要他認罪
They want him to plead guilty
但這樣他就會被開除軍籍...
but then he'll get dishonorable discharge...
或者拒不認罪 那他肯定會進監獄的
Otherwise he fights them, he for sure goes to prison.
不管怎樣 他都會被人們稱作懦夫
Either way, they'll call him a coward
我不知道他怎麼能那樣活下去
and I don't see how he can live with that.
謝謝 多蘿西
Well, thank you, Dorothy.
如果你有機會跟他說話
If you get to talk to him,
告訴他 我們愛他
tell him that we love him
我們為他禱告
and that  we're praying for him.
為你們倆祈禱
We're praying for both of you.
我會的
I will.
再見
Bye-bye.
你能不要煩我嗎
Will you leave me alone?
你能走開嗎
Will you just go?
湯姆 你已經瘋了 簡直不可理喻...
Tom, you're out of your mind, you're delirious...
我當然是瘋了
Of course I'm out of my mind.
不然呢 我已經瘋了
What do you think I am? I'm out of my mind.
你給我滾出這間房 蠢女人
Will you leave this room? Stupid woman!
天哪 把槍放下
God! Put it down!
死女人 離我遠點
Get away from me, woman.
明白了 先生
I got that, sir.
我有什麼能幫您嗎 先生
May I help you, sir?
我想跟斯格羅夫准將說幾句話
I wish to speak to Brigadier General Musgrove.
沒有預約 是不行的
Not without an appointment you can't.
那是不可能的
That would be quite impossible.
能請你轉告他
If you would kindly tell him
托馬斯·道斯下士想跟他說幾句話嗎
Corporal Thomas Doss would appreciate a brief word.
他在參加一個很重要的會議
He is in a very important meeting.
在法國貝洛森林戰役中 我曾與他並肩作戰
I fought with him in France at Belleau Wood.
當時 他是我的上尉
He was my Captain.
求你了 女士 我有很重要的事
Please ma'am. It's... It's most vital.
謝謝你 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
外面有位叫做托馬斯·道斯的人想要見您
There's a man out there, Thomas Doss, wants to see you.
道斯
Doss?
很快就能結束
Be over in a minute.
你很快就能安全回家了
You'll be home safe and sound,
就像什麼都沒發生過一樣
like nothing ever happened.
我愛你
I love you.
本次聽證會 被告為戴斯蒙德·道斯二等兵
This is a hearing into the matter of Private Desmond Doss.
其罪名為
The charge is disobeying
不服從指揮官的多項指令
a series of direct orders from his commanding officer.
被告方做何辯護
How says the defendant?
道斯二等兵 希望做無罪辯護
Private Doss wishes to enter a "not guilty" plea.
是嗎 二等兵 我本以為已經談妥了
Is that so, Private? I thought this was agreed.
你打算認罪 達成協議
You wanted to enter some sort of plea bargain.
- 是的 長官 但我改變主意了 - 就這樣嗎
- Yes, sir. But I changed my mind.- Just like that?
你想繼續在軍事法庭上辯護嗎
You wish to proceed to a court-martial.
是的 長官
Yes, sir.
那後果自負 二等兵
Well, on your head, then. Private.
請繼續
Proceed.
法官大人
Your honor,
道斯二等兵
Private Doss
到處炫耀他的道德觀
waves his morality at us,
就像炫耀榮譽勳章
like it's some kind of badge of honor.
通過違抗
He flaunts his contempt
直屬指揮官的一系列指令
by directly disobeying
來顯示自己的輕蔑之情
a series of direct orders from his commanding officer.
與此同時 我們國家最出色的年輕人們
When the very best of our young men
正在戰場上 不惜生命 抗擊...
are sacrificing their lives against...
- 你還好吧 - 還好
- You okay? - Yes.
- 還在審議嗎 - 是的
- Are they still deliberating? - Yes, sir.
好吧 你把這個拿進去
Okay, now you go take this in there.
不行 非軍事人員不得入內
I can't. It's strictly military personnel.
那你要他們中一個拿進去吧
Well, then you get one of them to take it in.
他們不會幫忙的 他們都恨不能把他埋了
They ain't out to help. They're fixing to burying him.
軍事法庭只需詢問被告
There's only one question
一個簡單問題就可以了
that any military court need ask of the accused.
你要否認 自己曾違抗塞恩斯頓上校的直接命令嗎
Do you deny disobeying Colonel Sangston's direct orders?
你否認嗎 二等兵
Well, do you, Private?
不 長官 我不否認
No, sir. I don't.
那你到底在爭論什麼
Why are you contesting it, then?
你既然拒絕觸碰武器 那到底為什麼
Why is it so important to you, given your refusal to even
要加入戰鬥分隊呢
touch a weapon to serve in a combat unit?
因為在日本人襲擊珍珠港後
Because when the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor,
我也感同身受
I took it personal.
我認識的每個人 都熱血沸騰地想參軍
Everyone I knew was on fire to join up,
其中也包括我
including me.
在我的家鄉 有兩個人
There were two men in my hometown,
因為體檢不合格
declared 4-F unfit,
沒能入伍 而選擇了自殺
they killed themselves 'cause they couldn't serve.
之前 我在兵工廠工作
I had a job in a defense plant,
本來可以申請延期服役 但那是不對的
and I could've taken a deferment, but that ain't right.
當其他人都在戰場上 浴血奮戰時
It isn't right that other men should fight and die,
我卻在家高枕無憂 這樣是不對
that I would just be sitting at home safe.
我要報效祖國
I need to serve.
我有熱情也有能力 成為一名醫護兵
I got the energy and the passion to serve as a medic,
與其他人並肩戰鬥 同甘共苦
right in the middle with the other guys, no less danger,
只是...
just...
當其他人都在奪取生命時
while everybody else is taking life,
我將會拯救生命
I'm going to be saving it.
世界已經開始分崩離析
With the world so set on tearing itself apart,
而有人想要盡力 維持一點點原樣
it doesn't seem like such a bad thing to me
在我看來 這似乎並不是壞事
to want to put a little bit of it back together.
- 抱歉 先生 任何人禁止入內 - 不
- Sorry, sir, nobody is allowed to... - No,
你不明白 我的兒子是被告
You don't understand. My son is the defendant.
我明白 先生
I understand, sir.
但任何人禁止入內
But nobody is allowed...
我有重要的消息
I have information, that's important.
先生 你不能...
Sir, you are not allowed...
雖然你表達的精神值得讚賞
While the sentiments expressed are laudable,
然而被控的罪行 卻是無可爭辯 所以...
the facts of the charge seem incontestable, so...
外面發生什麼事了
What the hell is going on out there?
- 先生 - 讓他進來吧
- Sir. - Let him go.
那是一戰的制服
That's a Great War uniform.
是的 長官
It is, sir.
長官 我想讓您看看這個
Sir, I need to show you this.
我沒有冒犯的意思 先生
With respect, sir,
但您已經不再是軍人了
you are no longer a member of the military.
您不能參加這次聽證會 我很抱歉
You're unable to attend this hearing. I'm sorry.
現在軍隊真的是這樣了嗎 長官
Is that truly the way it works, sir?
你為國家而戰
You fight for your country,
失去了許多寶貴的東西
you lose so much that were dear to you,
然後你卻一文不值嗎
and then you're done with?
軍裝被遺忘 老兵被漠視
The uniform's forgotten. You have no voice?
您參加了里昂戰役嗎
You were at Lyons?
是的 長官 以及貝洛森林戰役
I was, sir. And at Belleau Wood.
兩次都被授予了勳章 我看到了 先生
Twice decorated. I see it, sir.
我想您是這位二等兵的父親
I take it you're the Private's father.
沒錯 長官 我是托馬斯·道斯
I am, sir. Thomas Doss.
那麼作為一名退役軍人
Then, as former military man,
您應該知道這裏的法律
you know there are laws here.
長官 我知道那些法律
Sir, I know the law.
我也知道 法律會維護我兒子應該有的權利
and I know my son is protected by those laws.
這些都是被憲法所保障的
They are framed in our constitution.
我相信這些法律 他也一樣
And I believe in them, as he does.
正是為了捍衛我們的法律 我才會去報名參軍
They are why I went and fought to protect them.
至少當初我奔赴戰場時 我是這樣想的
At least that's what I thought I was doing
因為 如果不是那樣
because if it wasn't for that
那我就不知道我為何而戰 長官
then I have no idea what the hell I was doing there, sir.
謝謝您 道斯下士
Thank you, Corporal Doss.
把信交給我吧
Let me have the letter.
您必須離開
You must go.
"國會法案保護
"The defendant's rights as a
被告所擁有 出於信仰拒絕服兵役的權利"
conscientious objector are protected by an Act of Congress."
"並且不能強迫他放棄這些權利
"And he cannot be compelled to waive those rights.
包括本案中
That includes in this case
他擁有的違反軍令拒絕拿起武器的權利"
his disobeying orders to bear arms."
簽名 斯格羅夫准將
Signed, Bridgadier General Musgrove,
華盛頓特區 作戰指揮部
War Services Commander, Washington, D.C.
上校
Colonel?
我撤回指控 長官
I withdraw the charges, sir.
那麼案件審理結束
Then this case is dismissed.
道斯二等兵 你被允許 可以手無寸鐵
Private Doss, you are free to run into the hell fire of
衝進硝煙瀰漫的戰場了
battle without a single weapon to protect yourself.
你將重拾責任
You may resume your duties
受訓成為一名醫護兵
and begin training as a combat medic.
- 他在哪兒 - 走了
- Where is he? - Gone.
他出來就直接離開了 我求過他留下來
Straight after. I begged him to stay.
- 我告訴過他 你肯定想見他 - 我明白
- I told him you'd want to see him. - No, I understand.
等你回家了 告訴他 我愛他
When you get home, you tell him I love him.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
你一定要回家 回我身邊
You better come home to me.
# 山姆大叔微微笑 平靜似小孩 #
Uncle Sam is smiling. Peaceful as a child
# 但千萬不要把他惹惱 #
But never get him rowdy.
別唱了 大明星
Cut it out, Hollywood.
閉嘴吧
Shut up.
- 現在你想玩了嗎 - 拜託 別唱了
- So now you wanna play? - C'mon pipe down.
- 閉嘴吧  夥計 - 閉嘴
- Shut up, man. - Shut up.
我發誓 大明星 我要斃了你
I swear to God, Hollywood, I'll shoot you.
用襪子堵上嘴 可以嗎
Put a sock in it, will you?
等我們到了再高歌也不遲
Save the choir for when we get there.
真是掃興
Killjoy is here.
都讓開
Give 'em room.
- 讓開 - 借過
- Clear! - Clear! Move aside.
九十六步兵團
The 96th...
就剩這麼點兒人了
Or what's left of them.
我們就是要去輪換這些人
These are the guys we are replacing.
- 看起來沒問題  - 安全
- Seems good to me. - Clear.
- 沒問題 - 很好
- As gold. - Good.
一切安全 中士
All clear, Sarge!
格洛弗上尉
Captain Glover.
我是曼威爾中尉 來自九十六步兵團
Lieutenant Manville. 96th.
我們來接受您的指揮 長官
We've been assigned to you, sir.
好的
Okay.
給他們弄些吃的 快點
Let's get these men some chow. Come on.
是 長官
Yes, sir.
- 這位是豪威爾中士 - 很高興見到你
- This is Sergeant Howell. - Good to meet you, sir.
- 請坐 - 哪位是道斯
- Sit down. - Who's Doss?
坐下吧
Sit down.
在那邊
Over there.
你就是道斯
You Doss?
我是爾文·塞克特
Irv Schecter
你 我還有佩奇
You, and me and Page here
是這片區域僅剩的醫護兵了 所以...
are about the only medics weg ot left in this area. So...
我想我們將要團結協作
I guess we're going to be working together.
你們剛剛從前線下來嗎
You just come off the line?
那裏怎麼樣
What's it like?
我問 那裏怎麼樣
I said, what's it like?
鋼鋸嶺嗎
Hacksaw?
我們攀爬了六次
We climbed up six times.
六次 都被他們擊退
Six times, they threw us off.
上次進攻之後 九十六步兵團已經所剩無幾
Last time, there wasn't anything left of the 96th.
他們是禽獸
They're animals.
散發惡臭的禽獸
Stinking animals.
日本人不在乎自己的死活
Nips don't care if they live or die.
他們悍不畏死
They want to die.
他們不斷地發起衝鋒
They keep coming at you.
而且從不放棄
And they ain't never going to give up.
從不
Never.
來 夥計
Here. Hey, buddy.
這些日本人專門瞄準傷員
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
取下你所有的紅十字標記
Lose all your red cross markings.
對於擊殺醫護兵 日軍有額外獎賞
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
那塊白布太顯眼了
That white's a bull's-eye.
我給你找了個新頭盔
Here, I got you a new helmet .
通用尺寸
One-size-fits-all.
那就是我們的目標
That's our objective.
鋼鋸嶺
Hacksaw Ridge.
只要拿下它 也許我們就能拿下衝繩
We take it, maybe we get Okinawa.
拿下衝繩 我們就拿下了整個日本
We get Okinawa, we take Japan.
稍事休息
Take a breather.
我們的海軍弟兄們 會先替我們轟炸他們
Our pals in the Navy are gonna soften them up for us.
沒人能從這種攻擊中活下來
Nobody can survive that shit.
他們可以
Oh, but they can.
中尉
Lieutenant.
堡壘在這裏 這裏 還有這裏 對嗎
these bunkers here, here and here. Is that accurate?
這裏有三個...
Yeah, there's three...
沒錯 長官 也許比地圖上再往後點 但...
Yes, sir. Maybe they look further back, but it's all...
在上面 情況完全不同
it's all different up there.
發射完畢 上尉
All clear, Captain.
大兵們
Gents.
出發
Move out!
這是血
It's blood.
那還用說
No shit.
我們不是在堪薩斯州了 小妹妹
We're not in Kansas anymore, Dorothy.
繼續爬
Keep climbing.
來 把你的手給我
Here. Come on, give me your hand.
讓一下
Make way.
- 布朗 - 怎麼
- Brown. - What?
把這個給傑索普
Get this to Jessop.
下士 給你
Corporal, here.
敵人來襲
Incoming!
趴下
Get down!
他們到底在哪裏
Where the hell are they?!
我什麼都看不見
I can't see nothing.
你問住我了 兄弟
Beats me, pal.
他媽的到底在哪裏
Where the fuck!
醫護兵 快來
Medic, help!
我們在這邊
We're over here.
用你的手按住這裏
Put your hand right here.
用你的手壓住別放 傑克
Put your hand on there, Jack.
加油 堅持住
Come on, come on
堅持住 我們會把你送到掩體那裏
Come on. We're... We're gonna get you under cover.
堅持住 跟我走
Come on. Come with me.
跟我走 傑克
Come with me, Jack.
繼續前進 前進
Keep moving forward! Move!
我什麼都看不到
I can't see anything.
那個是敵人嗎
It's that one?
不知道 只管開槍
I don't know, just shoot！
好了 我們走
All right, let's go.
維托 來這裏 來這裏
Vito. Come here. Come here.
媽的
Oh shit!
道斯 維托受傷了
Doss, Vito's down.
我來了
I'm coming.
好了 我來了
Okay. I'm here.
讓開 別擋著
Get out of the way!
你受傷了嗎
You hurt?
我沒事
I'm fine.
堅持住 我在這裏 拉爾夫
Come on! I got you, Ralph.
深呼吸
Just breathe.
Just breath.
深呼吸 拉爾夫
Just breathe, Ralph.
沒事的 沒事的
It's okay. It's okay.
深呼吸
Just breath.
我就在這裏 我會救你的 堅持住
I got you. I got you. Come on.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
給他一劑嗎啡 然後就走吧
Give him a shot of morphine and move on.
他根本就撐不過一天
He's not going to last a day.
求求你 道斯 不要
Please. Please, Doss, no.
不 不要拋下我
No. Don't leave me.
不要拋下我 求你了 不要拋下我
Don't leave me. God, please don't leave me. .
我還有孩子
I've got kids!
求你了 不要
Please! Please don't!
不要拋下我
Please, don't leave me!
我不會離開你
I ain't going anywhere!
我會帶你回家 我會救你的 拉爾夫
I'm going to get you home. I got you, Ralph.
明白嗎
Okay?
我會帶你回家
I'm gonna get you home.
我這就給你注射嗎啡 這就注射嗎啡
Here comes the morphine. Here comes the morphine.
很快就不疼了 拉爾夫
It's going to kick in real quick, Ralph.
我們馬上轉移你
We're gonna get you shifted.
擔架
Stretcher!
起來
Get up!
繼續前進 孩子
Keep moving, son.
我走不動 我受傷了
I can't. I'm wounded.
你屁事都沒有
There's nothing wrong with you.
該死
Shit!
別動 小子
Hang on, kid.
快走
Move!
待著不動 只能等死
A soldier who doesn't is a dead one.
快走 走 走
Move. Go. Go. Go.
這傢伙有優先權
This guy's a priority.
交給我們吧 我們來負責
We got him, we got him.
- 放這裏 - 把他放下 放在這裏
- Here. - Put him down. Put him down here.
優先權 你沒聽過傷員分類嗎
A priority? You haven't heard of triage?
在我們送他下去之前 他就會堅持不住了
He'll be dead before we get him down.
你怎麼知道呢
you don't know that!
送他下去
Get him down!
好嗎
All right?
- 好吧 好吧 - 好的
- Okay. Okay. - Okay.
- 你去吧 - 好的
- Go! - Okay.
快去吧
Go!
沒事了 夥計 我們會帶你回家
It's all right, buddy. We're going to get you home.
醫護兵
Medic!
救救我 救救我
Help! Help!
我覺得 如果我們看不到他們
I figured if we can't see them,
那他們也看不到我們
then they can't see us neither.
救救我 救救我
Help! Help!
我受得很重 兄弟
I took it bad, man.
我來了 弗蘭克 你哪裏受傷了
I got you, Frank. Where you hit?
我覺得他們能看見 聰明蛋
I think they just did, smart ass!
- 道斯 快來 - 快來
- Doss, come on. - Come on.
來搭把手
Give me your hand here.
趴下 長官
Get down, sir.
就在這裏
Over there!
堡壘就在那裏
The bunkers!
我看到了 最好蹲下 長官
I see them. Better stay down, sir.
我發現堡壘了
I got 'em!
就在我們前方
Dead ahead!
是的 長官 我也看到了
Sir, Yeah. I see them too.
盡可能靠近堡壘
Push in as close as you can.
然後全力進攻
Give them everything you've got.
我會派出作戰隊 從側面包抄他們
I'll send in the weapon's team to flank them.
待著別動 你會沒事的 好嗎
You keep that tight. You gonna be right as rain. All right?
我來吧 道斯
I got him, Doss.
我來
I got him,
我們走吧 來 放在這裏
Here we go. Come on. Come sit over here
你還好吧
Hey, you doing okay?
沒問題
Okay.
準備 發射
And, fire!
趴下
Down!
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
- 你來負責這個 - 是 長官
- You, get on it. - Yes, sir!
幹掉他們 開火
Take 'em. Go. Fire!
投彈
Throw!
掩護
Cover!
上 快上 鬼二 進那個壕溝 待在那裏
Go, go. Go, Ghoul. Get in the hole. Stay there.
上 史密提 我們會掩護你 快躲閃
Go, Smitty, we'll cover you. Leapfrog.
掩護
Cover.
炸藥包
Satchel!
- 鬼二 - 安全
- Ghoul! - Clear.
加油 堅持住 堅持住 鬼二
Come on, stick it. Stick it, Ghoul.
掩護 掩護
Cover! Cover!
王八蛋
Son of a bitch.
掩護他
Cover his ass.
醫護兵 醫護兵 救救我
Medic! Medic! Help me.
衝啊
Go!
- 上啊 - 來吧
- Let's go! - Come on!
醫護兵
Medic!
我來了 用手壓住這裏 用手壓住
I'm here. Put your hand on it. Put your hand on it!
上 上 快上
Go, go, go!
鬼二 鬼二
Ghoul. Ghoul.
你沒事吧 你那裏受傷了
You're okay? Where you hit?
你頭被撞了下 沒事的
You got a bump on the head, that's okay.
你叫什麼名字
What's your name?
- 安迪 - 全名呢
- Andy. - Andy what?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
外號是什麼
Also known as?
- 鬼二 - 鬼二
- Ghoul. - Ghoul.
鬼二 你沒事的 你沒事的
Ghoul, you're okay. You're okay.
幹得不錯 兄弟們
Good job, men.
幹得漂亮
Good work.
今晚好好休息
Dig in for the night.
只要我們守住這裏
We hold this spot.
明天就能掃平整個山嶺
We mop up the rest of the ridge tomorrow.
現在 孩子們
Okay boys.
都給自己找個舒服的安全窩
Find yourself a nice safe hole.
躲在掩體裏 或者待邊上也行
In or near the bunker.
每兩小時換崗放哨
Rotate watch every two hours.
我們都不知道外邊還有什麼
We don't know what's out there.
所以 盡量放低身體
Heads down, asses lower.
任何不說英語的人 都格殺勿論
Shoot anything that don't speak English.
包括格雷斯嗎 中士
That includes Grease, Sarge?
尤其是他
Particularly him.
我不管你是要撒泡尿 還是蹲大號
I don't care if you need to take a piss or a dump.
都不能獨自出去
It ain't safe to go out there alone.
道斯 你他媽要去哪裏
Where the hell you going, Doss?
報告中士 外邊還有很多傷員
Still more wounded out there, sarge.
我跟他一起去
I'll go with him.
機靈點 小心行事
Be smart, keep your ears down.
好了 大家先找地方吧
All right, let's find a spot.
開戰不到十五分鐘 瓦拉利和亨利就死了
Rinnelli and Henry dead in the first 15 minutes.
直接掛了
Just straight off.
真是乾脆
It's straight off.
彼德森
Peterson.
大眼
Popeye.
斯坦福和墨菲
Stanford and Murphy.
佩奇和昂格爾
Page and Unger.
還有拉斯頓.
Ralston
"和平年代 黑髮人送白髮人"
"In peace sons bury their fathers."
"戰爭到來 白髮人送黑髮人"
"In war fathers bury their sons."
別說這些喪氣話了 行嗎
You wanna stop spouting that crap?
沒有任何作用
It don't help none.
是啊
Yeah.
你說的沒錯
Yeah, you got that right.
在這是沒用
Not here.
讓我來吧
Give me that.
喂
Hey!
這位腹部受傷
We got an abdominal wound.
這兄弟需要輸點血
This lad is gonna need some plasma.
- 沒問題 - 交給我們吧
- You got it. - Leave him with us.
好的 你安全了
Okay. You're okay now.
他們會照顧好你的
They got you.
我們要不要找個地方 吃點東西
Should we find a hole and dig in?
是個好主意
Sounds good to me.
把鋼盔戴上吧
Put your helmet on.
你不來點嗎
You ain't gonna eat that?
我不吃肉
I don't eat meat.
你吃吧
Help yourself.
你當然不吃肉了
Of course you don't.
她可真是漂亮
That's one heck of a dame.
你真是配不上這個美人
You know you're fighting out of
你知道這點 對嗎
your weight class with her,don't you?
是的 我知道
Yes, I do.
可別這麼跟她說
Don't tell her that.
她要是和我這樣的人在一起 肯定會更幸福
She'd be much happier with a man like me anyway.
沒錯 不過等她認清你就不會了
Yeah, until she got to know you.
有時候 我確實挺混蛋的
I'm an asshole sometimes.
只是有時候嗎
Sometimes?
你說的沒錯 好吧
You're alright. Alright.
這些日本人很狡猾
These Japs are sneaky.
我來放第一班哨
I'll take first watch.
你先休息會吧
And you get some shut-eye.
肯定是場噩夢
Hell of a dream.
我夢到 敵人用刺刀殺死了我
Dreamed I got myself skewered.
而我卻毫無辦法
I couldn't do nothing.
槍就在這裏
Rifle's just there.
不會咬人的
It won't bite.
不對 它會的
Yeah, it will.
看看周圍死的人
Look around you.
在經歷這一切之後
After what we've just been through,
任何正常人 就會拚命想要武器
any sane man would be screaming for a weapon.
我可沒說過 我是正常人
I never claimed to be sane.
我爸爸是個酒鬼
My daddy is a drunk.
多年以來 他一直想戒掉
He fought it for years,
但始終沒能成功
but it kinda got a hold of him hard.
所以脾氣很糟糕
Made him mean.
至少你還知道自己父親是誰
Least you knew him.
而我父親卻可能是十來個男人中的任意一個
Mine could've been any one of the ten guys
而且他們誰都不配 所以...
and none of them would worth a damn, so...
所以 是你媽媽把你養大的嗎
So, your momma raised you?
我記得她
I knew her.
但在我五歲時 她就把我送進了孤兒院
But she gave me to an orphanage when I was five.
從此就再沒見過她
Never saw her again.
我學會了麻利做事
I learned how to act quick.
學會了迅速識人
Learned how to judge people quicker,
但卻看錯你了 大錯特錯
and I got you very wrong.
我爸經常揍我和我哥
My daddy used to beat me and my brother
太陽上山的時候打 太陽下山的時候抽
just because the sun rose and then whip us because it set.
這點我都能忍
I could take that...
但當他對我媽動手的時候
but when he would do it to our momma...
你給我滾開 死女人
Get away from me, woman!
夠了 再也不許這樣
That's enough. No more.
聽見了嗎
Do you hear me?
你他媽的開槍啊
Pull that damn trigger.
不要 戴斯蒙德 住手
Don't, Desmond. Stop!
但你並沒有殺了他嗎
But you didn't kill him?
在我心裏 已經殺了
In my heart, I did.
所以 在那之後 我向上帝發誓
So that's why I made my promise to God,
我絕對不會再碰槍了
I ain't never gonna touch a gun again.
我還是不跟你講我的事了 因為你就是個瘋子
Well, I ain't giving you mine, 'cause you're crazy.
狗娘...
Son of a...
王八蛋
Son of a bitch！
撤 撤 快撤
Go! Go! Go!
快撤 快撤 都快撤回來
Move! Move! Get your asses over here!
我們也... 我們撤 快撤 撤
Why don't we... let's go. Go! Go!
撤退 回撤 快撤
Fall back, fall back! Go!
他們從地道裏出來的
They're coming from underground!
探照燈 這裏是B6 請求立即支援
Searchlight, this is Baker Six. Request immediate support.
目標位置 YT5-1-5
Target is at Yoke-Tare-Five-One-Five.
難道你不知道...
Don't you notice...
當然 我當然知道我們正在這鬼地方
Yes! Yes, I notice that's where the hell we are,
但我們很快就要守不住了
but I don't expect to be here much longer!
我請求了炮火支援
I called an artillery strike!
撤退 快撤 快撤
Fall back! Move! Move!
撤退 全體 撤退
Fall back! Men, fall back!
這有敵人
Get some!
兄弟 我在這裏 就在這裏
Hey, buddy. I'm right here, right here.
好吧
Okay.
掩護我
Cover me!
快撤 快撤
Go! Go!
別過來 孩子
Get out of here, kid!
來這裏 孩子
Come here, son!
你知道該怎麼辦
You know what to do.
用力按住
Keep pressure on it.
不用 我不需要血漿
No! Don't need plasma.
給他用吧
Give it to him!
在那邊
Over there!
我沒事的 去吧
I'll be okay. Go.
快去
Go!
- 胖球 - 怎麼了
- Greasy! -What?!!!
- 把爾文送回去 – 好的 沒問題
- Get Irv back! - You got it, okay.
那好 咱們回見
Okay, see you soon.
來吧 快來
C'mon. C'mon!
我們得馬上撤離 來吧 加油
We gotta move right now! C'mon! C'mon!
撤退 撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
撤 撤 快撤
Go, go, go!
小心手雷
Fire in the hole.
換這個
Change.
你得盡快離開這裏
You'd better get the hell out of here!
快撤 快撤
Move! Move!
我好怕 我好怕啊
I'm scared. I'm scared.
這個能止疼
It's going to help the pain.
別 別 不要 你不能這樣
No! Don't! Dont'! Don't you do that!
堅持住
C'mon!
堅持住 史密提 堅持住
C'mon, Smitty, you stay with me!
我們走 我們得撤離
Let's go. We gotta move!
幫我把他送下去
Hey! Help me get him down.
Help me get him down!
快點 抬他下去 快點
Come on. Let's move. Come on.
沒法幫你了 兄弟 他不行了
Can't help you buddy. He's gone.
- 不會的 - 快點 我們得趕緊離開這裏
- No. - Come on! We gotta get out of here!
快走
Let's go!
快點 走吧
Come on, let's go.
快點 所有人
Come on! Everyone!
快下懸崖
Off the ridge!
主啊 你要我怎麼做呢
What is it You want of me?
我不能領會
I don't understand.
我沒法傾聽
I can't hear You.
救護兵 救救我
Medic! Help me!
救救我
Help me!
主啊 救救我吧
Help me, Lord!
好吧
Alright!
- 有人會好好照顧你的 - 輕點 輕點
- You're in good hands. - Easy does it. Easy.
六... 八
Six... Eight...
十四
14.
- 馬上把他們送到安全的地方 – 遵命 長官
- Get these men secured immediately. - Yes, sir.
二等兵福特 下來了幾個人
Private Ford. How many?
只有三十二人下來 長官
32 only came down, sir.
- 老天爺 - 走吧
- Good Lord. - Let's go!
- 讓他們上車吧 - 遵命 長官
- Let's load 'em up. - Yes, sir.
哈里
Harry.
我是戴斯蒙德
It's Desmond.
我們會救你的
We gonna fix you up.
保持呼吸 好嗎
You just gotta keep breathing. Okay?
上校要見你 長官
Colonel wants to see you, sir.
我得用你們的吉普車
I need your jeep.
你們兩個留下
You two stay here.
繼續蹲守 注意敵人動向
Keep watch, keep your eyes peeled for Japs.
不過 這裏...
No. But the...
留下 守著
Stay here! Keep watch.
- 遵命 長官 - 遵命 長官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
救命 救救我
Help! Help me.
小心
Watch out!
放心吧
I got you.
把你的手放在這裏 用力按住
Put your hand on it. Keep pressure on it.
我很快就回來 好嗎
I'm coming back. Okay?
好的
Okay.
- 這裏需要幫忙 – 快去
- We need hands over here. - Move
快 快去 快去
Move! Move! Move!
- 你先下去 – 把他抬下來
- You just go down. - Bring him down.
慢點 哥們兒們 慢點
Easy, fellas. Easy.
下來了
Here we go.
你們把他抬下來
You got him down.
好了 兄弟們 準備好 數到三
Okay, guys. Let's go. On the count of three.
一 二 三 放
One-two-three. Move.
快來 請醫護兵過來
Help, medic over here!
沒事的 哥們 堅強點
It's okay, buddy, hold it together.
我們到崖邊了 艾瑞克
We're at the edge, Eric.
你待著別動 好嗎
You just sit tight, okay?
沒事了 艾瑞克 你不會有事的 兄弟
You're okay, Eric. You're okay, buddy.
好傢伙 這也許能行
Son of a gun, this is going to work.
一條腿上套一個 艾瑞克
One for each leg, Eric.
我們很快就能給你做好繩套
We're going to get you dressed up in a jiffy
然後把你送下去
and get you down.
弄好了
I got you.
這就好了 艾瑞克
I got you now, Eric.
你得相信我 艾瑞克 你必須要相信我
You have to trust me now, Eric. You'll have to trust me.
日本人
Japs!
別開槍 是自己人 別開槍
Hold on, it's one of ours. Hold on.
快過去 快過去
Let's go. Let's go.
這就到了 這就到了 這就到了
I got you. I got you. I got you.
堅持住
Come on.
有我在 你會沒事的
I got you. You're okay.
你會沒事的
You're okay.
漢克
Hank!
又下來一個
Another one.
上校 請求停止對鋼鋸嶺的炮火轟炸
Colonel, call off the the artillery attack on Hacksaw.
當時我們來不及撤離
Couldn't call it in.
還有一百多人尚未撤離
There's still over a 100 men left out there.
告訴他們 停止對鋼鋸嶺的炮火轟炸
Tell them to call off the artillery on Hacksaw.
AB1 完畢
Able-Baker-One over.
坐下吧 傑克
Sit down, Jack.
我給你拿點喝的
I'll get you a drink.
我們沒有掩護了
We just lost our cover.
日本人來了 我們得趕緊撤離 快點
They're stirrin', we got to move. Come on.
是時候了
About time.
不斷有傷者被送下來
They just keep coming.
快抬起來
Okay. Pick it up.
我來幫你
I got this.
道斯
Doss.
救我
Help.
救救我
Help me.
你必須相信我
You're gonna have to trust me.
吸氣
Take a breath.
兄弟 我們走
Let's go, buddy.
我們走
Let's go.
傑克 你並不知道上面的兄弟是死是活
Jack, you don't know if your men up there are dead or alive.
沒有援軍 你們不能貿然回去
You can't go back up there without reinforcement.
你可能會害了剩餘的手下
You'll end up killing the rest of them.
那就給我增援啊
Then give me the reinforcement.
我已經沒有人 明白嗎
I don't have any fresh men, okay?
沒有可調配的軍隊了
I don't have any troops.
今天 三支隊伍全軍覆沒
3 batallions got wiped out today.
新調配的人手 最快也要一天後才能到達
And it'll take more than a day to get men in here.
我需要更快點
I need them faster than that.
沒事的 沒事的 沒事的
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
沒事的 沒事的
It's alright. It's alright.
沒事的
Everything's okay.
嗎啡 對你有好處
Morphine. It's good.
噓
Shhh.
潘尼克 潘尼克
Pinnick, Pinnick.
潘尼克 我是道斯
Pinnick. It's Doss.
我是道斯 小聲點
It's Doss. Be quiet.
別說話
Be quiet.
是我 你受傷了嗎
I got you. Are you hit?
是的 我看不見
Yeah. I can't see.
小聲點 千萬別出聲
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
別動
Hold still now.
讓我來
I got you.
堅持住
Hold tight.
好了
There you go.
現在試試 睜開眼睛
Try now. Try now.
我還以為我瞎了
I thought I was blind.
小聲點
Keep it down.
你還能走嗎
Can you walk?
我不確定
I don't know.
- 我們必須盡快離開這裏 快起來 - 好
- 'Cause we gotta get out of here. Come on. -  okay!
很好 好了 我們接住你了
Good. Okay, we got you.
你安全了
We got you.
泰德
Hey, Ted.
是我 我是戴斯蒙德
It's me. It's Desmond.
我會幫你的
I'll fix you up.
- 你準備好離開這裏了嗎 - 當然
- You ready to get out here? - Sure I am.
主啊 求求你
Please, Lord,
讓我再救一個吧
help me get one more.
Help me get one more.
求求你 讓我再救一個吧
Please, help me get one more.
再救一個
One more.
讓我再救一個吧
Help me get one more.
再救一個
One more.
讓我再救一個吧
Help me get one more.
再救一個
One more.
又一名傷者
Coming through.
這些傷員究竟都是哪來的啊
Where the hell these guys coming from?
鋼鋸嶺
From Hacksaw.
我以為他們已經撤離了
I thought they pulled out.
並非所有人都撤離了
Not all of them.
上面有個瘋子 不停地在送傷員下來
Some nut's up there dragging wounded from the top.
甚至還送下來幾個日本人
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
不過他們沒挺過來
They didn't make it.
傷員會直接送到你這裏的
Get back with you directly.
小心 小心
Easy. Easy.
好了 出發
All set. Move out.
- 走吧 - 去哪裏
- Let's go. - Where to?
快進來
Get in here.
到處都是日本人
There's Nips everywhere.
他媽的
Son of a bitch.
玉米稈二等兵
Private Corn Stalk.
你還真是讓人驚訝啊
You're nothing if not full of surprises.
- 你要來點嗎啡嗎 - 廢話
- You want some morphine? - Hell, yes.
要麼來針嗎啡 要麼給我一槍
That or a bullet.
好的
Okay.
好了
There.
沒事了
There you go.
好了
Alright.
別緊張 讓我看看
Easy. Let me see.
這裏傷得如何 好吧 不算太糟糕
How's this doing? Okay. Not bad.
讓我看看
Let me see.
看起來比較糟糕 實際還好
Looks much worse than it is.
女孩們還是會願意親你的
Girls will still want to kiss you.
中士
Sarge,
你能再撐會兒嗎
you okay here for a while?
當然 我沒事
Yeah, I'm fine.
你帶他先走
Get outta here.
我會回來的
I'm coming back.
準備好了嗎 走吧
You ready? Let's go.
我們走 來吧
You and me. C'mon.
上尉 您得看看這個
Captain, something you gotta see.
整晚 我們的人就這樣不斷地被送下來
Our guys have been coming down in droves all night.
大明星居然還活著
And Hollywood's here.
我本以為再也見不到他了
I never thought I'd see that guy again.
快跟我來 他就在這
Come on, follow me. He's right here.
到底怎麼回事
What the hell is this?
你好 長官
How you doing, sir?
嘿 上尉
Hey, Cap.
上尉
Captain.
很高興見到你 孩子
It's good to see you, kid.
格洛弗上尉 長官
Cap Glover, sir.
孩子 你是怎麼下來的
How did you get down, son?
是道斯
Doss.
豪威爾也還在上面
Howell's still out there.
什麼 是豪威爾和道斯救了你們嗎
What? Howell and Doss did this?
不 長官 只有道斯
No, sir. Just Doss.
- 只有道斯 - 只有道斯
- Just Doss? - Just Doss.
沒錯 道斯 那個膽小鬼
Yeah, Doss, the Coward.
你還真是不死心 是嗎
You're like gum on a shoe, ain't ya?
把槍給我
Give me this.
現在才練習打靶 有點太晚了吧 你不覺得嗎
It's a bit late for target practice now, don't you think?
跳上來
Jump on it.
你是在開玩笑嗎
You're kidding?
不 我要拖著你走
No, I'm going to drag you.
來吧
Let's do it.
- 準備好了嗎 - 好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
我們走
Let's go!
日本人來了
We got company.
快走
Come on.
抬起胳膊
Arms up.
玉米稈 你是在逗我吧
You gotta be kidding me, Corn Stalk?
"小子 你是在打單套結 不是做內衣"
You're tying a bowline, boy, not building a bra.
加油
Come on!
準備好了嗎
Ready?
下去吧
Get off!
- 放我下來 - 是的 中士
- Put me down! - Yes, Sergeant.
豪威爾中士
Sergeant Howell.
道斯還在上面
Doss is still up there.
怎麼回事
What the hell?
日本人在追他
He's got Japs on his tail.
我們接住他了
We got him.
沒事了 沒事了
It's good. It's good.
沒事了 沒事了 道斯
Woah. It's okay. It's okay. Doss.
沒事了 道斯 你安全了
Come on, Doss. You're safe.
- 好 - 過來吧 道斯
- Okay. - Come on, Doss. Come on.
- 戴斯蒙德 沒事了 - 沒事了
- Desmond, it's alright. - It's alright.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
- 小心 - 小心 小心
- Easy. - Easy. Easy.
坐吧 坐這裏
Here. Come on.
快坐下
Take a seat.
你受傷了嗎
Are you wounded?
沒有
No.
快把這位士兵送到醫療帳篷
Let's get this soldier to a hospital tent, right now.
來吧 慢慢來
Come on. Easy now.
小心一點 大家讓讓
Easy. Easy. Make some space.
我們需要有人來幫忙 清理下這裏
We need someone to come and clean up in here.
爾文在哪裏呢
Where's Irv?
爾文
Irv?
你是說塞克特 那個醫護兵嗎
You mean Schecter, the Medic?
他沒挺過來
He didn't make it.
死於休克
He died of shock.
沒有血漿了
No plasma.
很遺憾
I'm sorry.
我一直以為 你只是個瘦弱的孩子
All I saw was a skinny kid.
我根本不瞭解你的為人
I didn't know who you were.
你對這個國家所做出的貢獻
You've done more than any other man
超過了其他任何服役的軍人
could've done in the service of his country.
我這輩子 從來沒有如此誤解過別人
And I have never been more wrong about someone in my life.
我希望有朝一日 你能原諒我
I hope one day you could forgive me.
明天我們要繼續攻打鋼鋸嶺
We have to go back up tomorrow.
我知道 明天是你的安息日
I realize that tomorrow is your Sabbath.
他們很多人都不像你這樣 擁有虔誠的信仰
Most of these men don't believe the same way you do.
但他們堅信
But they believe so much
你對自己信仰的虔誠
in how much you believe.
你在鋼鋸嶺上的所作所為
What you did on that Ridge
簡直堪稱奇跡
is just nothing short of a miracle,
他們也希望能享有這份奇跡
and they want a piece of it.
如果你不去 他們是不會上去的
And they're not gonna go up there without you.
上尉 你們為什麼還沒行動
What the hell is your delay, Captain?
十分鐘前 你們就該發動攻擊了
You were supposed to begin that assault 10 minutes ago.
我們還在等待 長官
We're waiting, sir.
等什麼
Waiting for what?
等待道斯二等兵 為我們祈禱完畢 長官
For Private Doss to finish praying for us, sir.
道斯二等兵正在為你們祈禱
Private Doss is praying for you?
他媽的誰是道斯二等兵
Who the hell is Private Doss?
準備出發
Let's go to work.
跪下
Down!
跪下 跪在地上
Get down! Get down on the ground!
立刻跪下
On the ground. Now!
躺下 快躺下 我有嗎啡
Lay down! Lay down! Lay down! I got the morphine.
快走 快走 快帶他離開這裏
Let's go! Let's go. Let's get this man outta here.
快 快
Go! Go!
我的《聖經》
My Bible...
我的《聖經》 我的《聖經》
My Bible. My Bible...
停 停 快停下
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
我的《聖經》 我的《聖經》
My Bible. My Bible.
知道了
Okay.
戴斯蒙德 你馬上就能回家了
You going home, Desmond.
我們拿下了鋼鋸嶺
We've taken the Hacksaw.
等等 等等 戴斯蒙德
Hold up! Hold up! Desmond.
戴斯蒙德
Desmond.
當時 我一直在祈禱
I was praying the whole time.
我一直向主祈禱
I just kept praying,
"主啊 求求你 讓我再救一個吧"
"Lord, please help me get one more."
每當救下一個人之後
When I got this,
我就繼續祈禱 "主啊 求你 讓我再救一個吧"
I said "Lord, please help me get one more".
在我看來
I would say anyone is wrong
試圖改變任何人的信仰 都是不明智的
to try to compromise somebody's conviction.
不論是在軍隊 還是在其他地方
I don't care whether it's the army or what it is.
只要你秉承自己的信仰
When you're on a conviction,
那就絕不是玩笑
that is not a joke.
而是真正的你
That's what you are.
雖然我對他說了許多
Even though I said those things
說他應該拿槍上戰場
to him in regard to carrying a rifle,
如果他不拿槍
then... then he would never be my...
我就絕不會和他一起並肩作戰
by my damn side at all unless he had a rifle.
但最終
But then, in the long run,
我卻發現 他是最英勇的士兵之一
finding out that he was one of the bravest persons alive.
而最後 還需要他來救我
And then to have him ended up
這簡直太諷刺了
saving my life was the irony of the whole thing.
鮮血從他的臉龐和眼睛上流下
Blood had ran down through to the fella's face and eyes.
當時 他躺在那裏 呻吟著 不停地叫醫護兵
He was laying there just groaning and calling for a medic.
我從水壺中倒了些水 拿了些紗布
I took the water from my canteen and got some bandages,
幫他洗了臉
and I washed his face.
當他眼裏的鮮血 被擦乾淨之後
And when I was washing his eyes,
他睜開了眼睛
his eyes came up.
他簡直高興壞了
Man, he just lit up.
他說 "我還以為我瞎了"
He says "I thought I was blind."
而當時他臉上的笑容
And if I hadn't got anything more out of the war
對我而言
than that smile he gave me,
就是最好的回報
I wouldn't have been well repaid.
掃碼關注翻托邦字幕組微博，獲取更多影視資源資訊
翻譯  Yatamisaki
翻托邦字幕組長期招募英日翻譯及後期，詳情請見微博置頂
翻譯  旺財
翻譯  熱水袋
翻譯  POPPINS
翻譯  遐思飛飛
翻譯  柒一四
翻譯  sherry
時間軸  被窩裏的玉玉
特效  熱水袋  煙斗oo0
壓制  煙斗oo0
發佈  小本 熊超哥
校對  勇氣之熊
監製  Yatamisaki
血戰鋼鋸嶺
梅爾·吉普森
作品